ATANDA ABDULLAHI ADEWALE

Vision Expert | Data Scientist

+33 0749499978 https://github.com/waledroid

abdullahi atanda@etu.u-bourgogne.fr

41 rue Lavoisier, Le Creusot, 71200, France



PROFILE

Computer vision engineer skilled in real-time object detection. Expert in modular Python for scalable development. Led a waste sorting initiative, improving detection accuracy by 20% with a compressed Vision Transformer. Passionate about working with an organization integrating machine learning into core operations or decision-making.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Research Engineer

WASORIA Le Creusot 71200, France

02/2024 - Present

- Present and research innovative Detection Transformer architectures to improve real-time object detection's speed and accuracy
- Optimizing models in real-time for edge devices through refinement and compression
- Dataset creation and augmentation to enhance accuracy and performance

Information Technology Officer

02/2013 - 09/2022

Federal Radio Corporation of Nigeria (FRCN) Ikoyi, Lagos operations

- Website development and management (radionigerialagos.gov.ng)
- Live audio and video streaming of live on-air studios on social media
- Technical support, office networking, Advert Tracking System

Consumer Insight Research

10/2011 - 09/2012

Cadbury Nigeria Plc, Ikeja, Lagos

- Monthly Regional Market Analysis using Nielsen Global FMCG Database
- Coordinating Qualitative and Quantitative Research Projects in Nigeria
- Marketing Support Functions Statistical Analysis and Research

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Image Processing
- Object Detection, segmentation and Tracking
- Frameworks: PyTorch, Keras, MMDetection3, Detectron2, Diffusers, RoboFlow SuperVision
- Pose Estimation

- Data analysis and visualization
- Feature engineering
- Time series analysis
- Camera Calibration
- Medical Imaging (PyDicom, MONAI)

- Machine learning SOTA algorithms
- Optimization techniques
- Natural language processing with Spacy
- Model deployment and maintenance
- Front-end web (React, Next, Tailwind, Firebase)
- Big data technologies (Spark)
- Cloud computing (Google Cloud)
- Git version control
- Agile project management

EDUCATION

Applied MSc in Data Engineering for AI Data ScienceTech Institute School of Engineering DSTI, France Masters of Science M2 in Computer Vision and Robotics Université de Bourgogne, Le Creusot, France Postgraduate Diploma in Computer Science University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria In view 07/2024

PROJECTS

Real-Time Pedestrian Detection in Traffic Surveillance:

- Achieved high accuracy using YOLOv5 in identifying pedestrians in multi-scenes, leveraging a small INRIA Person Dataset
- Involved in real-time analysis of video footage from a surveillance camera

Household waste detection system:

- An accuracy of 87.5% was achieved in recognizing 8 distinct waste objects.
- This success was attributed to advanced compression techniques, including knowledge distillation and feature integration extraction from a pre-trained SOLOv2 model into the Segment-Anything SAM model by leveraging a ZeroWaste Dataset and a custom-designed dataset.

ATTRIBUTES

- Excellent data management and multi-tasking ability
- Team collaboration and communication
- Expert in Microsoft Excel and SPSS (Report & Analysis)
- Committed to cutting-edge research and innovation in computer vision.

LANGUAGES English (Native) French (B1 Level)

INTERESTS Tech News, VR/AR, and Traveling

REFERENCES Available on request.

ATANDA ABDULLAHI ADEWALE

Expert en Vision | Data Scientist

+33 0749499978 https://github.com/waledroid

abdullahi atanda@etu.u-bourgogne.fr

41 rue Lavoisier, Le Creusot, 71200, France



PROFIL

Ingénieur en vision par ordinateur, spécialisé dans la détection d'objets en temps réel. Expert en Python modulaire pour le développement évolutif. A dirigé une initiative de tri des déchets, améliorant la précision de détection de 20 % grâce à un Vision Transformer compressé. Passionné par le travail avec une organisation intégrant le machine learning dans ses opérations principales ou ses processus décisionnels.

EXPÉRIENCE PROFESSIONNELLE

Ingénieur de Recherche en Apprentissage Automatique

02/2024 - Présent

WASORIA Le Creusot 71200, France

- Présentation et recherche sur les architectures innovantes de Detection Transformer pour améliorer la vitesse et la précision de la détection d'objets en temps réel
- Optimisation des modèles en temps réel pour les dispositifs edge grâce au raffinement et à la compression
- Création et augmentation de jeux de données pour améliorer la précision et les performances

Responsable Informatique

02/2013 - 09/2022

Federal Radio Corporation of Nigeria (FRCN) Ikoyi, Lagos

- Développement et gestion de sites web (radionigerialagos.gov.ng)
- Diffusion audio et vidéo en direct des studios sur les réseaux sociaux
- Support technique, mise en réseau des bureaux, système de suivi des publicités

Recherche en Insight Consommateur

10/2011 - 09/2012

Cadbury Nigeria Plc, Ikeja, Lagos

- Analyse mensuelle du marché régional à l'aide de la base de données Nielsen Global
- Coordination des projets de recherche qualitative et quantitative au Nigeria
- Fonctions de soutien marketing Analyse statistique et recherche

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Traitement d'image
- Détection, segmentation et suivi d'objets
- PyTorch, Keras, OpenMMLab Detection, Detectron2, Diffusers, RoboFlow SuperVision
- Estimation de la pose

- Analyse et visualisation de données
- Ingénierie des caractéristiques
- Calibration de caméra
- Imagerie médicale (PyDicom, MONAI)

- Algorithmes SOTA en apprentissage automatique
- Techniques d'optimisation
- Traitement du langage naturel avec Spacy
- Déploiement et maintenance de modèles
- Développement web front-end

- Technologies Big Data (Spark)
- Informatique en cloud (Google Cloud)
- Contrôle de version Git
- Gestion de projet Agile

COURS / CERTIFICATIONS

Master appliqué en Data Engineering pour l'IA. Data ScienceTech Institute School of Engineering DSTI, France Master of Science M2 en vision par ordinateur et robotique Université de Bourgogne, Le Creusot, France Diplôme de troisième cycle en informatique University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria

PROJETS

Détection des piétons en temps réel dans le cadre de la surveillance du trafic :

- Grande précision de l'identification des piétons dans des scènes multiples grâce à YOLOv5 et à un petit ensemble de données INRIA sur les personnes.
- Participation à l'analyse en temps réel de séquences vidéo provenant d'une caméra de surveillance

Système de détection des déchets ménagers :

- Une précision de 87,5 % a été atteinte dans la reconnaissance de 8 objets de déchets distincts.
- Ce succès a été attribué à des techniques de compression avancées, y compris la distillation des connaissances et l'extraction de l'intégration des caractéristiques d'un modèle SOLOv2 pré-entraîné dans le modèle Segment-Anything SAM en tirant parti d'un ensemble de données ZeroWaste et d'un ensemble de données personnalisé.

ATTRIBUTS

- Excellente gestion des données et capacité à effectuer plusieurs tâches à la fois
- Collaboration et communication au sein de l'équipe
- Expert en Microsoft Excel et SPSS (rapports et analyses)
- Engagé dans la recherche de pointe et l'innovation dans le domaine de la vision par ordinateur.

LANGUES Anglais (langue maternelle) Français (niveau B1)

INTÉRÊTS Actualités, VR/AR, voyages

RÉFÉRENCES Disponible sur demande.